# **GREG GABELMANN**

499 Pinehill Road, Oliver, BC, V0H 1T5 250-258-3180 – greg.gabelmann@gmail.com

I have over a decade of experience delivering multi-tier applications. My expertise is with Java and other server-side technology, but over the years I've worked with numerous languages and frameworks. I enjoy all parts of the software development life-cycle and believe in frequent releases to Production.

## **CAREER HISTORY**

## **Travel Throughout South America and Mexico** (2018/07 – 2018/12)

Visited Argentina, Chile, Peru, Ecuador, and Mexico. Along the way, studied for the DELE Certification (Spanish Level A1 Diploma).

#### Software Developer 4, Central 1 Credit Union (Permanent, 2016/12 – 2018/06)

Technical Lead for "User Management", a hosted webapp which allows Credit Unions to administer and manage their staff's rights.

- Designed and led the implementation of User Management R4.0's flagship feature, with completion 4 months ahead of schedule.
- Improved security by fixing vulnerabilities that were on OWASP's Top Ten list.
- Improved performance with strategic use of caching and multi-threading.
- Improved code quality by taking ownership of the Technical Debt backlog.
- Mentorship of team-members through individual coaching and group lunch-and-learns.
- Tech summary: Java, JSP, Spring, SAML, SQL Server, and LDAP.

### Senior Java Developer, PageFreezer Software (Permanent, 2015/08 – 2016/12)

Senior Developer for PageFreezer's flagship SaaS, which allows Customers to archive websites and social media for compliance and eDiscovery.

- Added features to support the archival of complex websites, which enabled PageFreezer to win contracts with clients such as BlackRock.
- Reduced server load by 75% by tackling performance hotspots throughout the stack.
- Improved server stability by using LXC/LXD containers to isolate archive jobs.
- Wrote a new job scheduler which fixed long-standing bugs and could report real-time metrics.
- Created dashboards that let Customer Support proactively fix broken archive jobs.
- Tech summary: Java, JSP, SQL, Berkeley DB Java Edition, MySQL.

## **Lead Web Engineer, X Plus Z** (Permanent, 2013/12 – 2015/07)

Team Lead for off-shore X Plus Z employees in China. My team was contracted to Electronic Arts and developed web portals for titles such as Dragon Age: Inquisition, FIFA World, and The SIMS.

- Collaborated with Product Owners to write Stories, provide estimates, and prioritize backlogs.
- Full-stack development including analysis, development, code reviews, and merges.
- Provided first-line support for Production sites, including fixes for Critical bugs.
- Created and supported Docker containers / Vagrant images for developers and QA.
- Tech summary: AngularJS, Grails, Java, PHP + Symphony, MySQL, Git, Scrum.

## **Java Developer, Travel Underwriters** (Contract, 2012/10 – 2013/05)

Worked on Travel Underwriters' hosted web app, "Venture", which allows Customer Service Representatives and external Partners to sell travel insurance nationwide.

- Designed and implemented a scalable search solution for Venture by embedding Lucene Search.
- Designed and implemented an Alfresco CMS integration component for Venture. The Business Users could then query for Policies and manage their lifecycles.
- Tech summary: Java, JEE, Lucene Search, Alfresco CMS, JSF, Seam, Jboss, Hibernate, SVN, Scrum.

## **Software Engineer, Elastic Path** (Permanent, 2010/10 – 2012/06)

Worked on "EP Commerce", a highly customizable ecommerce application with support for HTTP, REST, and SOAP clients.

- Added "recurring billing products" (eg, \$10/month) to EP Commerce. New product attributes were added, the pricing engine was changed, and the frontend HTML/Javascript was updated.
- Updated EP Commerce's inventory subsystem to journal quantity changes instead of doing inplace edits. "Rolling up" the true quantities at runtime was more scalable under heavy load than locking.
- Tech summary: Java, Spring, OpenJPA, Liquibase, MySQL, SVN, Kanban.

## **Software Engineer, SAP BusinessObjects** (Contract, 2007/10 – 2010/09)

Worked on "MDAS Server", a middle-tier application that supports pluggable OLAP Servers and exports functionality over HTTP and CORBA.

- Added first-class support to the MDAS Server for SAP's Business Warehouse OLAP Server. This major project took several years and involved dozens of people.
- Worked daily with remote teams in France and Germany to incorporate critical components into the MDAS Server.
- As Build Master, maintained Cruise Control for the MDAS Server.
- Tech summary: Java, CORBA, Spring Framework, Junit, Mockito, Perforce, Scrum.

#### **Software Engineer, Epic Data** (Permanent, 2005 – 2007)

Worked on "P3 Suite", a client/server application for inventory and purchase order management.

- Developed new features and fixed bugs for the wireless handhelds used by floor workers. The handhelds used Java 1.1 + Swing and communicated with the server using RMI.
- Increased the quality of P3 Suite by advocating agile practice such as daily builds, test driven development, and customer involvement.
- Tech summary: Java, Swing, HTML, CSS, Tomcat, SimpleORM, Oracle DB, Junit, CVS, Scrum.

# **EDUCATION**

- Bachelor of Science, Double Major in Computer Science and English, University of Victoria. Graduated in 2000 with Distinction.
- Two years of Co-op experience at four different companies.
- Completed the course "Building F# Applications" (https://ude.my/UC-9JOG0JPX)
- Studying for the AWS "Cloud Practitioner" Certification.
- Studying for the DELE Certification (Spanish Level A1 Diploma).